Previously on "The Mentalist"...
"超感警探"前情提要...
She told me Red John has a tattoo
她告诉我血手约翰有纹身
on his left shoulder-- three dots.
在他的左肩... 是三个点
That's my leverage.
这是我的优势
Gather all five suspects together
把五个嫌疑人同一时间
at the same place, same time,
集中到同一地方
and then start checking for the tattoo.
再检查纹身
How do we do that?
怎么做?
Meet me at 8:00 on Thursday night.
周四晚八点来见我
Fine.
好
Thursday night at 8:00.
周四晚八点
I'll need your help. Well,then you've got it.
- 我需要你帮忙 - 好 没问题
If you don't show up, he will assume you're Red John.
如果你不出现 他会认定你是血手约翰
If I do this, will you and Jane drop
如果我去了 你和Jane会放弃
the whole that "I'm Red John" business?
"我是血手约翰"的想法吗?
For once and for all.
最后一次
You really think you've got him?
你确定能抓到他?
I do.
确定
I want to be there when you end this.
你结束这一切时 我要在场
I was hoping you'd say that.
我正希望你这么说
Red John.
血手约翰
Nothing would give me more pleasure than to be with you there tonight.
没什么能比我那晚在你身边 更让我荣幸
Red John... has a tattoo.
血手约翰... 有纹身
Three dots on his left arm.
左手臂上有三点
And you all...
你们...
Are gonna show me...
都要给我看...
Now.
马上脱
Let's go. Come on.
快点 来吧
That's it. Take it off.
行了 脱吧
Nonsense.
没道理
It's not what you think.
不是你想的那样
You got it wrong.
你弄错了
I'm not Red John.
我不是血手约翰
Patrick,wait. Patrick!
Patrick 等等 Patrick!
Look... here.
看... 这里
Look.
看
On your feet.
站起来
Over with those two.
去和那俩一起
Oh... God.
哦... 天
You stay there.
站那别动
Okay,you three...
好 你们仨...
Over against that wall-- now.
靠墙站好... 快点
Call the fire department and E.M.T.s
打给消防队和急救中心
Let them know that there's multiple casualties,and set up a perimeter.
告诉他们多人受伤 拉警戒带
Give me your flashlight. I-I'm going in.
给我你的手电 我要进去
Jane jane
Jane Jane
Agent Smith.Agent Smith, it's Teresa Lisbon.Are you okay?
Smith探员 Smith探员 我是Teresa Lisbon 你还好吗?
What happened?
怎么了?
There was an explosion. The E.M.T.s are on their way.They're gonna help you.
发生了爆炸 救护员正赶来 他们会救你的
- Don't move! - What?
- 不许动! - 什么?
Put your hands in the air, or I'll shoot! Do it!
把手举高 不然我开枪了! 快点!
Okay,listen,I don't know what you're talking about.
听着 我不知道你在说什么
You're clearly making a big mistake.
你明显搞错了
Which way did Smith go?
Smith去了哪?
- Oh,my God,Lisbon. - We have to find Smith. He's Red John.
- 天啊 Lisbon - 我们要找到Smith 他是血手约翰
Ah... I'll get help.
呃... 我找人来帮忙
Jane?
Jane?
Can you hear me?
能听到吗?
Jane? Come on.
Jane? 拜托
=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=http://ytet.org=-   proudly presents
-=伊甸园美剧论坛 http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=http://ytet.org=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- sync:邦德猪
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组-歆组=- 翻译: 粒粒尘 紫月 皮皮 Scenery Shirley 校对: 黄沙舞风 时间轴: 邦德猪
the mentalist season6 ep07
超感警探 第六季 第7集
You okay?
你没事吧?
I'm fine.
我没事
The doctors say Jane's stable.
医生说Jane情况稳定了
There's no major trauma or anything.
没受重伤
He's just not awake.
只是他一直没醒
They found the remains of three people.
他们发现三个人的尸体
Positive I.D.s for Bret Stiles, Ray Haffner,and Thomas McAllister.
很可能是Bret Stiles Ray Haffner和Thomas McAllister
Are you sure? I would think Bret Stiles would survive a nuclear attack.
你确定? 我还以为Bret Stiles 即使遭遇核袭击也能存活
The bodies are all burnt to a crisp,but the crime techs did spot D.N.A. tests.
尸体都已经烧焦了 但鉴证部门取到了DNA
Coroner's office checked it against medical records.
法医和医疗记录做了对比
Stiles,Haffner,and McAllister are all positively dead.
Stiles Haffner和McAllister 确实是死了
Uh,what about Smith? Any sightings?
那Smith呢? 有发现吗?
Not yet. Rigsby and Van Pelt are on it.
暂时没 Rigsby和Van Pelt在跟进
Sir?
长官?
- Ah,thought I might find you here. - Are you all right?
- 啊 我就知道能在这找到你 - 你没事吧?
Uh,I'm fine. I could use a cup of coffee,actually.
我没事 其实我想喝杯咖啡
Would you go and get me one?
你可以帮我买一杯吗?
We're just about to coordinate the manhunt for Smith.
我们正在协商追缉Smith的事
Well,you should just go and get him.
你应该去抓住他
Well,I'd like to stay here,sir.Well,are-- Cho and the team-
我想留在这里 长官 小周和队里的人...
- they can handle it. - Are you refusing a direct order?
- 他们可以处理 - 你不服从命令?
Well,no.
不是
- No,I just want to stay here with him. - Wh-why don't you listen a little more closely?
- 不 我只是想在这里陪着他 - 你为什么不听清楚一点?
I am ordering you to get out there,
我命令你从这里出去
put your team together, and get Smith.
召集你队里的人 抓住Smith
Jane? Jane? Where's the damn call button?
Jane? Jane? 呼叫按钮在哪?
I'll--I'll get the nurse.
我 我去找护士
Jane.
Jane
hey boss
嘿 长官
Our working theory is that Red John brought in the bomb to kill Jane and the other suspects.
我们认为是血手约翰带了炸药 想要杀死Jane和其他嫌疑人
Okay,but how?
好 但怎么弄的?
Chances are,Red John snuck the bomb in on his person.
可能血手约翰把炸弹藏在他的同伙身上
Crime techs have pulled fragments of the bomb casings from the walls-- very small fragments.
鉴证从墙上找到了炸弹碎片 非常小的碎片
This tells us that the explosive was dense,high-powered.
这说明爆炸是密集的 杀伤力极大的
That doesn't sound homemade.
不像是自制的
No. Military grade's my bet,which means it could be traceable.
不 我想是军事级别 这样的话 就是可追踪的
These are the most likely sources.
这是最有可能的渠道
- Check for any recent thefts of missing explosives from any of them. - All right,will do.
- 查下他们最近有没有炸药失窃或丢失 - 好 这就去
- Got something? - Yeah.
- 有发现? - 嗯
Lisbon wounded Smith before he escaped.
Smith逃走前被Lisbon射中
He's walking around with a bullet.
他身体里有颗子弹
Oh. Well,hospitals have to declare gunshot wounds,
医院接收枪伤人员需上报
so he can't go to an E.R.
他不能去急救室
Right,so he needs a doctor who'll keep quiet.
是 所以他需要个懂得闭嘴的医生
Smith's based here in Sacramento,so I looked into some of his old cases around town.
Smith被派遣到萨市 所以我查了下他在这里的旧案子
He was part of a task force that arrested Dr. Alek Lavrov last year in south Sac.
他是去年在南萨市逮捕 Alek Lavrov医生的一员
A Dr. Feelgood writing illegal oxycontin scripts.
那是个会开非法兴奋剂的医生
- So? - So the case went bad,
- 然后? - 然后案子没能定罪
evidence was lost, and Lavrov walked.
证据丢失 Lavrov无罪释放
So Smith knows exactly where to find a doctor who won't talk to the cops. Okay,let's go check it out.
Smith知道在哪能找到不向警察告密的医生 好 我们去查查看
It's not what you think.
不是你想的那样
I'm not Red John.
我不是血手约翰
Patrick,wait. Look.
Patrick 等等 你看
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Lisbon.
Lisbon
There was an explosion at your house.
你家发生了爆炸
How long have I been out?
我昏迷多久了?
12 hours.
12个小时
Reede Smith is Red John.I saw the tattoo on his shoulder.
Reede Smith就是血手约翰 他肩上有那个纹身
He's not the only one.
他不是唯一一个
McAllister has one,too.
McAllister也有纹身
He's dead. So are Stiles and Haffner.
他死了 Stiles和Haffner也死了
- And Bertram. - Bertram?
- 那Bertram呢 - Bertram?
He has the tattoo as well.
他肩上也有纹身
Oh,my God.
老天
He was just here.
他刚才还在这儿
He was standing over you.
他就站在你旁边
He--he was trying to get me to leave.He was gonna kill you.
他想把我支开 原来他想杀你
Where are my clothes? Slow down,okay?
- 我的衣服呢? - 慢点 好吗?
Just-- No,it's okay. We don't have time.
只是 不 没事了 我们没时间了
Jane. Jane.
Jane Jane
Where are my clothes?
我的衣服在哪里?
This is Teresa Lisbon.
我是Teresa Lisbon
Put out a statewide alert for the apprehension of Reede Smith and Gail Bertram.
发一份全境范围的通缉令 通缉Reede Smith和Gail Bertram
Yes,Director Bertram.
确定 是Bertram局长
Approach with caution.They're considered armed and dangerous.
务必小心 他们可能携带武器 极端危险
One of them is Red John.
他们其中一人是血手约翰
***
IVAN LAVROV诊所
- god. - Move along,ma'am. Police business.
- 天呐 - 请离开 女士 警察执行公务
God!
天呐!
Yes.
对
The bullet is still inside you.
子弹还在你身体里
No crap! Get it out!
少废话! 快弄出来!
This is going to hurt.
那会很疼
Are you sure you won't take something for the pain?
你确定不要什么止痛药吗?
No...
不要...
No. I gotta stay sharp.
不要 我必须保持清醒
As you like.
如你所愿
God!
天!
Tiger,tiger.
猛虎 猛虎
Smith in there?
Smith在这里?
Yeah. He's screaming his head off.
是 他快把屋顶叫破了
He won't be a problem. How you wanna do it?
他不是问题 你打算怎么做?
I just got word from inside CBI.
我刚从CBI内部得到消息
Couple of agents are coming here right now looking for Smith.
有两个探员正往这儿来找Smith呢
So what do we do? We hurry.
- 那我们要怎么做? - 我们动作要快
You go get him. I'll run interference if CBI shows.
你去找他 我在外面守着 以防CBI探员干扰
You got it.
明白
Take him out the back. Do it there.
把他带到后面再做掉
He made me do this. I'm innocent. Shut up.
- 是他强迫我的 我是无辜的 - 闭嘴
I would have called the police as soon as he left.
我打算等他一走就报警
I don't want any trouble! Quiet!
- 我不想惹上任何麻烦 - 安静
You association?
你是同伴吗?
Tiger,tiger. Why didn't you call us?
猛虎 猛虎 你为何不给我们打电话?
Funnily enough, I got trust issues.
有趣的是 我不太信任别人
Hey,you gotta trust your friends.
你必须相信你的朋友
I'm here to help you. Can you walk?
我是来帮你的 你还能走路吗?
I need to sew him up. He'll bleed.
我得给他缝合伤口 他会流血的
Ah... I can walk.
我能走
Detective Cordero,right?
Cordero警探 是吧?
Agent Rigsby.
Rigsby探员
How are ya?
怎么样?
He's,uh,Sac P.D. worked the Kirkland shooting.
他是萨市警局负责 Kirkland枪击案的警探
This is Agent Grace Van Pelt.
这位是Grace Van Pelt探员
What brings you to south Sac?
你们怎么会来萨市南边?
We're chasing up a lead on Reede-- Reede Smith.
- 我们追查的线索与Reede... - Reede Smith 又叫血手约翰
Looks like we beat you to the punch.
看来我们抢在你们前头了
One of my guys is in there getting him right now.
我们的人正在里面抓他呢
You want us to cover the back?
需要我们去后面打掩护吗?
No. No,we got it. You sure?
- 不 不用 我们能搞定 - 你确定
Hey,we might not be CBI, but we know what we're doing.
我们虽然不是CBI 可我们知道该怎么做
Okay. Excuse me.
好 失陪一下
Yep?
啥事?
Rigsby,where are you?
Rigsby 你在哪儿?
Outside the doctor's office. Looks like Smith's inside.
就在诊所外面 看样子Smith在里面
Are there policemen with you?
有其他警察和你一起吗?
Yeah. Why?
有 为何这么问?
Okay,listen carefully.
仔细听我说
Do not trust anyone in law enforcement.
不要相信任何执法部门的人
Anyone at all. Do you understand?
任何人都不行 明白吗?
You got it. Thanks.
明白了 多谢
Let's,uh,go take a look around back.
我们去后面看一眼
Wait a minute.
等会 你们要去哪儿?
Car's back this way.
车在后面的路上
Everything's taken care of.
一切都处理好了
We got a safe house nearby, fresh clothes,a doctor...
我们在附近有个安全屋 干净衣服 还有医生...
A trip out of town.
出城路线也准备好了
A safe house,huh?
安全屋 哈?
You know,I said that to someone once.
知道么 我也曾向某人这么说过
Yeah? What happened after that?
是吗? 那之后发生了什么?
I shot him six times in the back.
我向他背后开了六枪
Come on.
来吧
Damn it.
我靠
Drop your weapon!
放下武器!
Stop!
站住!
- You all right? - Yeah! You good?
- 你没事吧? - 没事 你还好吧?
Yeah.
还好
Smith got away during the fight.So did the detective.
Smith趁乱逃跑了 那个警探也溜了
Boss,they were trying to kill Smith and us. Why?
老大 他们想杀Smith和我们 为什么?
I don't know. Check the shoulder.
- 我不知道 - 检查肩膀
What?
什么?
Ask him to check the left shoulder.
让他检查左肩
Have Rigsby take his shirt off and look at his shoulder.
让Rigsby把他衬衣脱下来 检查肩膀
Lisbon wants you to check his left shoulder.
Lisbon要你检查一下他的左肩
What the hell?
这是什么鬼东西?
He's got it. He's got the tattoo.
他肩膀上有纹身
Boss,what's happening?
老大 出什么事了?
All right,bring him in and don't let anybody else get to him.
好 把他带回来 不要让任何人接近他
Bring him in.
把他带回去
What do we know about the cop who attacked you?
查到那个袭击你们的 那个警察的什么线索吗?
This is the one we caught. Officer Paul Wiehagen.
我们抓的就是他 Paul Wiehagen警官
Six years on the force. Exemplary record,
当兵六年 履历光辉
a couple of commendations, no real discipline problems.
受过几次嘉奖 没有违纪问题
What about the other one-- Detective Cordero?
另一个呢 Cordero警探?
Put a call in to his captain.Said he called in sick an hour ago.
给他上司打了电话 说他一小时前请病假了
And still no sign of Bertram.
还是没有Bertram的踪迹
Let's focus on the one we do have.
先把注意力放在抓到的这个身上
Maybe Jane will figure it out.
也许Jane能弄清楚
Did someone send you to kill Reede Smith?
是不是有人派你来杀Reede Smith?
I got nothing to say.
我没什么可说的
Why were you gonna murder him?
你为什么要杀他?
What about the tattoo? What's it mean?
那个纹身是怎么回事? 有什么含义?
You're not a big talker. I get it.
你不擅言辞 我明白了
Loose lips sink ships and all that.
言多必失
The bad news is, you have a lousy poker face.
坏消息是 你长了一张差劲的扑克脸
So we're gonna play a little game of show-and-tell.
所以我们要玩一个边看边说的小游戏
I'm gonna tell you something, and you're gonna show me with your face
我会跟你讲一些事情 你会用表情告诉我
whether I'm right or not.
无论我说对还是说错
That sound fun?
很有趣吧?
You ever steal anything?
你曾经偷过东西吗?
Did you ever cheat on your girlfriend?
你曾经对女朋友劈过腿吗?
Hit her?
打过她吗?
Do you like causing pain?
你喜欢制造疼痛吗?
I never hit a woman in my life.
我这辈子从没打过女人
Do you belong to a secret organization of cops and other government officials?
你属于一个秘密组织? 由警察和官员组成的?
Yes.
是的
You've committed crimes on behalf of that organization before.
你以前为这个组织犯过罪
Right?
对?
Agent Smith is a member also...
Smith探员也是组织一员...
The organization sent you to the doctor's office to kill him... right?
组织派你去医生办公室杀了他 对
CBI director Gail Bertram is also a member.
CBI局长Gail Bertram也是组织成员
You don't know.
你不知道
Too low on the totem pole,huh?
你级别太低 嗯?
Agent Reede Smith is Red John.
Reede Smith探员是血手约翰
Don't know.
你不知道
Gail Bertram's Red John.
Gail Bertram是血手约翰
That tattoo on your shoulder is the membership sign.
你手臂上的刺青是成员标记
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
Right again.
我又说对了
There's a password,too--something you say as a greeting or a...
你们还有一个暗语 用来认出彼此或
Distress signal.
求救
"Tiger,tiger".
"猛虎 猛虎"
Get out of my head.
从我的意识里滚出去
A secret society of dirty cops.
一个黑警秘密组织
And Red John's a member.
血手约翰是其中一员
Partridge.
记得Partridge吗?
He said "tiger,tiger" to me right before he died.
他临死前对我说"猛虎 猛虎"
Hmm. Yes. Yes.
嗯 对
He was asking for help
当时他在求救
in the hopes that you were a member.
希望你是组织成员
But if he had a tattoo,
但如果他有刺青
it would have been in the autopsy report.
验尸报告应该有记载
Well,you can't trust a file.
文件不值一信
We have to see it.
我们必须亲自看到
I'll have Cho track down the body.
我会让小周追查尸体的情况
But Partridge could be buried by now.
但Partridge现已下葬
Well,have Cho bring a shovel.
让小周买铲子回来
The team's looking for Smith, Bertram's on the run.
大家都在寻找Smith Bertram还在逃亡
So who's Red John?
那么谁是血手约翰?
Is it Bertram or Smith?
是Bertram还是Smith?
I need to look them both in the eye.
这两位我都要盯紧
Yeah,the coroner released his body,like,two days ago.
对 大概两天前 验尸官送来了他的尸体
- Murder victim,huh? - Yeah.
- 谋杀案的受害者 对吗? - 对
I figured. That's why we held him for so long.
我猜也是 所以我们一直留着尸体
Good thing you got here today.
今天你有好东西可以看
Tomorrow there won't be much left of him to look at.
要是明天 他就不剩什么能给你看了
Here we go.
就是他
Brett .
Brett
Give me a hand,huh?
帮把手 嗯?
He's all yours.
都是你的啦
Give me your knife.
借我把小刀
They dress 'em before we burn 'em.
他们火化他之前 给他穿了衣服
Don't ask me why.
别问我为什么给他穿衣服
Cho sent a picture.
小周发来一张照片
What does it mean?
是什么意思?
What do you think it means?
你觉得是什么意思?
What happened with Smith?
Smith怎么了?
They almost got him at his doctor's office.That CBI team showed up.
他们差点就在医生办公室里搞定他 但CBI小组出现了
Smith's in the wind.
Smith跑了
That's a good place to be.
跑得好
I've got some business in here,so wait for me.
我有点事要办 等我会儿
Ah. Thank you,Mr. Thomas.
啊 谢谢 Thomas先生
We haven't seen you for a while.
您好长时间没光临了
Yeah. It's nice to see you.
嗯 见到你真高兴
Smith could be anywhere by now.
Smith现在可能逃到了任何地方
I tried to trace the G.P.S. signal on his cell phone.
我尝试追踪他手机上的GPS
It's been dead for hours.
四个小时了 没有信号
A dirty F.B.I. agent like him has to have a burner.
他那样的FBI黑警一定有一次性手机
Dr. Lavrov says he didn't get the chance to sew Smith up.
Lavrov医生说他没来得及 帮Smith缝合伤口
He's still walking around with a bullet wound.
Smith仍带着子弹伤口奔逃
So he's in a bad way wherever he is.
所以无论他在哪儿 伤情都很糟糕
He'll get picked up by someone eventually.
他总会被什么人抓走
Yeah,but any cop who finds him...
对 但如果有警察找到他...
This is scary. We can't trust anyone.
太吓人了 我们不能相信所有人
Nope.
是啊
Agent Van Pelt.
我是Van Pelt探员
You gotta help me.
你得帮帮我
Agent Smith.
Smith探员
They're gonna kill me.I wanna surrender.
他们会杀了我 我想投降
Where are you?
你在哪里?
Downtown. Call Cho. He should be close.
在市区 给小周打电话 他应该在附近
Okay,we're on our way.
好的 我们马上来
Smith reached out to CBI.
Smith跟CBI联系了
He used the burner the association gave him.
他用了联盟给他的一次性手机
We were listening.
我们一直监听他
He's turning himself in.
他要自首
Yeah. Rat.
没错 他是叛徒
That CBI team is on its way to get him now.
CBI小组正去找他
Well,we can't have that. Where is he?
那可不行 他在哪?
He's in an alley not too far from here. Our good luck.
他在一条小巷里 离这里不远 我们运气不错
Does he know who you are?
他知道你是谁吗?
Nah,he didn't see me at the doctor's office.
不 他没在医生办公室里看到我
All right. You are now a CBI agent.
好的 你现在是CBI探员了
You want to come along? Could be fun.
你想一起来吗 一定很有趣
No. I have some other business to take care of.
不 我有别的事情要处理
- We'll meet up later. - You got it.
- 我们稍后会合 - 必须的
Can you get it right this time?
你懂我的命令吗?
Yes sir.
是的 长官
Agent Reede Smith?
Reede Smith探员?
You out there? Agent Van Pelt sent me.
你在吗? Van Pelt探员派我来
Who are you?
你是谁?
Agent Oscar Cordero,CBI.
Oscar Cordero CBI探员
I'm here to take you in.
我带你回去
You gotta keep me safe.
你必须保证我的安全
They're everywhere.
到处都有他们的人
Yeah.
对
We are.
到处都是
God...
天啊
Back of the car now.
马上到车后面
You didn't really think you could get away from us,did you?
你真的认为你能逃走?
You're a big boy. Do me a favor and get in the trunk yourself.
你不是小孩了 帮帮忙 自己进去
Just give me a second, will you?
稍等一下 可以吗?
You'll have a second in the trunk.
给你一秒钟进后备箱
Now don't make me do painful things to you.
别让我弄疼你
Get in the car!
进去!
I'm gonna need a deal. Full immunity.
做个交易 完全豁免权
I'm not saying a word unless I can walk.
除非我可以走出这里 否则我一个字都不说
So walk.
那走啊
What?
什么?
Get up off your ass and walk.
抬起你的屁股 走啊
But,hey,good luck getting out of the building before your friends catch up with you.
不过 祝你能在你的朋友们抓到你前 走出这个大楼
If you tell us everything we need to know,
要是你说出我们想知道的一切
I promise we will put you in a federal prison far away from California.
我保证会把你关在 远离加州的联邦监狱里
Someplace that you'll be safe.
在那里你会很安全
Five years ago, I hurt my back.
五年前 我背部受伤
I was helping my cousin move a stupid couch.
当时正帮我表亲搬一个该死的沙发
Doctor gave me some pain pills.
医生给我开了些止疼药
Turns out I liked them.
结果我很受用
I got hooked before I even knew what was happening.
不知不觉地上瘾了
So?
然后呢?
So...
然后...
I'm chasing a gangbanger down an alley in Carson Springs, and I'm out of it.
我当时正在Carson喷泉的一条小路上 追捕一名黑帮成员 我的瘾犯了
I mean,way out of it.
我意思是 很严重的瘾
I thought--I thought I was being followed.
我以为... 以为我被跟踪了
I shot a little girl.
我打死了一名小女孩
A 12-year-old girl.
12岁的小女孩
Local cops took my blood.
当地警方给我采血做鉴定
They had witnesses. They had me cold.
还有人证 我就被停职了
And then this detective,he reaches out to me and he says they can make it all go away.
之后有名警探找到我 说他们能解决这些事
And they did.
他们确实办到了
The blood tests, the witnesses--all of it?
血液检查 人证 所有事?
Hell,when they got done fixing it,
离谱的是 当他们处理完这事
the F.B.I. gave me a medal.
联邦调查局还给了我一个奖章
And exactly who are "they"?
"他们"到底是谁?
We call ourselves the Blake Association.
我们管自己叫布莱克协会
Why?
为什么?
"Tiger,tiger."
" 猛虎 猛虎"
"Tyger,tyger burning bright""
" 猛虎猛虎 明亮如火团锦簇"
from the poem by Blake.
出自布莱克的诗
Someone's a big fan of his, I guess.
我猜有人是他的铁杆粉
Well,who else is in the association?
还有谁是这个协会的?
Cops,judges,F.B.I. agents.
警察 法官 联邦探员
Anyone in law enforcement that needs a secret covered up.
执法机构中任何需要掩盖秘密的人
Like your drug habit.
比方说你的毒瘾
You need a favor, you ask for it.
你有什么需要就说话
You get asked to do something, you do it.
别人让你做什么 你就做什么
"Tiger,tiger."
"猛虎 猛虎"
Yep.
是啊
Well,is there somebody who's in charge?
组织由谁掌控?
Must be.
一定有
But I don't know who.
可我不知道是谁
I just know my little group. That's it.
我只知道我的小团体 就这么多
But I'm guessing there must be hundreds of us, maybe thousands.
不过我想我们有上百人 或许上千人
And nobody knows about it?
没人了解这个组织?
Bob Kirkland knew about it, didn't he?
Bob Kirkland清楚 是不是?
Go ahead,just say it. Unburden yourself.
快啊 说出来你就如释重负了
Yeah.
是的
He knew too much.
他知道的太多了
So I killed him.
所以我杀了他
Do you know that Red John's a member of the Blake Association?
你知道血手约翰是布莱克协会的一员吗?
Are you sure?
你确定?
Red John had a follower.
血手约翰有一名追随者
Rebecca Anderson.
Rebecca Anderson
Killed some of your guys about four years ago.
四年前杀了一些你们的人
Yeah,Sam Bosco and his team.
是的 Sam Bosco和他的小队
Them.
就是他们
Someone asked me to get F.B.I. credentials
有人让我去弄联邦调查局的身份证明
so that they could access CBI.
以便能进入CBI
Red John or someone who worked for him snuck into the CBI and poisoned Rebecca.
血手约翰 或是某个为他卖命的人 潜入了CBI 毒死了Rebecca
And you helped them?
你帮忙了?
I mean,that's when I knew.
那时我才意识到
I'd--I'd done a favor for a serial killer.
我给... 一个连环杀手帮了忙
Who asked you to get the credentials?
谁让你去拿身份证明的?
I don't know. It was a phone call.
不知道 电话里说的
That's the way the association works.
这就是协会的行事方式
You never know.
我们一概不知
You...
你们...
You're gonna be able to keep me safe,right?
你们能够保证我的安全 是吧?
That depends.
那要看情况了
Did you murder my wife and daughter?
你杀了我的妻女吗?
I did not murder your wife and daughter.
我没有杀你的妻子和女儿
I swear on my mother.
我以我母亲的名义起誓
Do you believe him?
他说的你信吗?
He confessed to murder.
他对谋杀供认不讳
Red John would never break like that,not even as an act.
血手约翰绝不会这么认怂 即使做戏也不会
- Well,if Smith isn't Red John... - That means we have work to do.
- 如果Smith不是血手约翰... - 那就有我们忙的了
And we need help. Who took over from Brenda Shettrick?
我们得找人帮忙 谁接手了Brenda Shettrick的工作?
In media relations? Why?
公共关系? 为什么?
Thank you for coming on such short notice.
感谢你们接到临时通知前来
We have CBI consultant Patrick Jane here,
我们请到了CBI的顾问Patrick Jane
who is here to report a development in the Red John case.
他将向我们报告血手约翰一案的进展
Thank you.
谢谢
Ten years ago,
十年前
the serial killer known as Red John killed my wife and daughter.
连环杀手血手约翰杀了我的妻女
Uh,we've been hunting him diligently ever since.
从那时起我们就在不懈地追捕他
Today we're pleased to announce that we--we finally have a name,a face.
今天 我们很高兴地宣布我们... 我们终于知道他的名字 长相
The director of the division of law enforcement,Gail Bertram,is Red John.
执法部门的主管Gail Bertram 就是血手约翰
He's armed and dangerous.
他持有武器 十分危险
If you see him, do not approach him.
要是你看到他 不要接近
Call the California Bureau of Investigation at once.
立刻通知加州调查局
Thank you.
谢谢
One question at a time.
一个一个地问
Excuse me mam.
请您回避 女士
So are we gonna talk about this?
咱们谈谈这件事?
Talk about what?
谈什么?
Bertram is Red John.
Bertram是血手约翰
Looks like.
看起来是的
And if Jane finds him, he's gonna kill him.
要是Jane找到他 他会杀了他
Yeah.
是啊
And we're good with that? Killing the boss?
咱们就束手旁观? 让他杀了头儿?
I am.
我没意见
Yeah.
我也是
Okay.
好吧
Just as long as we're on the same page.
大家说清楚就好
It's just weird,is all.
就是觉得有点诡异
Does Bertram smoke?
Bertram吸烟吗?
No,I don't think so.
不 不吸
People get them as gifts sometimes.
有时人们会收到这样的礼物
Van Pelt.
Van Pelt
A flash drive.Let's take a look.
是个闪存盘 咱们看看
There's only one file on the drive.
盘里只有一个文件
It's password-protected.
有密码保护
I'll have to brute-force it.
我得蛮力攻破它
Cool. I've been wanting to use my new F.P.G.A.
真棒 我早就想试试我的现场编程阵列
Your what?
你的什么?
Trust me, don't ask.
相信我 别问
And...
然后...
We're in.
打开了
Crap.
乱码
It looks like a list.
看上去像个清单
Names,maybe? Can you decode it?
可能都是名字? 你能破译吗?
I can try a few things...
我可以尝试几种方法...
but decoding is Jane's department.
但破译是Jane的专业
I'll send it to him.
我发给他
Here you go. This one isn't messing around.
给你 这酒很赞
Lots of peat.
大量熏泥煤烘烤
Yeah,that's pretty good. Can you put some rocks in it?
是啊 味道很好 你能放点冰块在里面吗?
Are you sure? This is some fine scotch.
你确定? 这可是上好的苏格兰威士忌
Yeah,I'm sure.
是的 我确定
**
那人看着挺像你
I need a ride.
我要辆车
We're en route to the bar now.
我们正在去酒吧的路上
Highway patrol shut down the freeways,
路警关闭了高速公路
so if he runs,we've got him, but what if he hides?
所以如果他跑路 我们就能逮到他 但如果他藏起来了呢?
Bertram killed the bartender in Citrus Heights.
Bertram在柑橘高地杀了酒吧招待
He's got an aunt with a house there.
他姨妈在那里有所房子
You think that's where he is?
你认为那是他藏身的地方?
She moved into a retirement home about six months ago,so her place is empty now.
她6个月前搬进了养老院 所以那房子现在空着
Sounds like a good place to hide. What's the address?
听上去是个藏身的好地方 地址是什么?
1408 Rosemary Street.
迷迭香路1408号
We're on our way. Get Cho and R.R.T. there now,and let the choppers know.
我们正开过去 让小周 和快速反应小组赶到那里 通知直升机组
- Is he here? - He's in there.
- 他在吗? - 如果在的话准没逃出屋子
I got Karl and a few guys in the back.
我让Karl和另外几人守在后门
- He's not going anywhere. - Do we trust them?
- 他跑不了 - 他们可靠吗?
I asked to see their shoulders and their tattoos.
我查看了他们的肩膀 没纹身
What are you doing here? I didn't call Sac P.D. S.W.A.T.
你们来这儿干嘛? 我没有叫特警
Well,someone asked for us.
反正有人叫了
Let's set up a command center right here!
我们就在这儿设立指挥中心!
Listen,everybody, I'm in charge!
大家请注意 这里由我负责!
That district's that's way across town. What the hell is going on?
那区域横跨整个城市 这究竟是怎么回事?
He did it. He called them in.
他干的 他叫来了特警
Well,why would Bertram call S.W.A.T. to his own location?
Bertram为什么要让特警 来他的藏身之处?
He didn't call in one S.W.A.T. team.
他叫的不是一队特警
He called all of them in.
而是所有的特警
This is a madhouse.
真是个疯人院
There's a whole 'nother unit setting up out back.
有另外一整个部门在那儿布置
We've lost control of the scene,boss.
我们失去了现场控制权 头儿
He's one of them. Bertram is one of them.
他就在里面 Bertram就混在他们中间
He's getting away. We gotta shut it down.
他要逃跑 我们得控制这局面
Nobody leaves!
谁都不能离开!
No one leaves!
一个都不行!
You're clear.
你安全了
Yeah...
是啊...
I need something to eat.
我得吃点东西
How about Chinese? I know a great place.
中餐怎么样? 我知道个好地方
Yeah,sounds good.
嗯 好啊
They found Bertram's clothes inside the house.
他们在房子里发现了Bertram的衣服
Looks like someone planted a S.W.A.T. team outfit
好像有人在他到达之前
in the house before he got there.
就把整套特警装备放在那里
And then called every S.W.A.T. and R.R.T. in the area.
然后呼叫了所有特警 和快速反应小组去现场
Any leads about who made all those calls?
有线索证明是谁干的吗?
Somebody who could pull a lot of strings at once.
某个能在瞬间一呼百应的人
Blake Association.
布莱克联盟
Boss.
头儿
May I have your attention, please?
请大家注意
Put down your phones and step away from your desks.
放下你们的电话 离开你们的办公桌
Now.
马上
I'm Special Agent in charge Teresa Lisbon.
我是这里的负责人 特别探员Teresa Lisbon
Who the hell are you?
你是哪位?
F.B.I. supervisory Agent Dennis Abbott.
FBI主管Dennis Abbott
Now I repeat,stand up and stand away from your desks...
现在我重复 站起身 离开你们的办公桌...
Please.
请了
We're in the middle of a manhunt for a dangerous fugitive.
我们正在追捕一个危险的逃犯
Now if you would like to assist--
如果你愿意协助-
The head of this alleged law enforcement organization is a murderer,
这个所谓的执法部门的主管是个凶手
and a member of a massive criminal conspiracy.
和一个重大犯罪组织的成员
Which included F.B.I. agents.
这个组织里也有FBI特工
Yes,and that's why the bureau sent me here from the Austin,Texas, office.
对 所以局里才把我从德克萨斯 奥斯丁分局派到这里来
To clean up the mess.
收拾这个乱摊子
I am holding in my hand a writ from a federal judge.
我手里拿着联邦法官签发的命令
The F.B.I.'s closing down your organization right now.
FBI将立刻查封你们的部门
All of you are relieved from your active duties
你们所有人都将被解除现职
as of this moment.
立即生效
You can't do that.
你不能这么做
I'm here to collect evidence.
我是来收集证据的
Don't get in my way.
别碍手碍脚
Let's go to work,fellas.
开始行动 伙计们
What's going on here?
这里出了什么事?
***
这是你的
Dennis Abbott,F.B.I. you must be Patrick Jane.
Dennis Abbott 我是FBI的 你一定是Patrick Jane
They've shut us down.
他们把这里查封了
We're gonna need to interview you at some point,
我们会找时间跟你面谈
but it can wait. We're gonna be here for some time.
但不急 我们会在这里待一段时间
Just don't leave town.
别出城就行
We have a killer to catch.
我们得抓凶手
Oh,well, that's our problem now.
哦 现在那是我们操心的事了
You had your chance to catch him and you blew it--
你曾有机会抓他 但你浪费了
if you were really trying.
如果你当时真的尽了力
That was my favorite cup.
那是我最喜欢的杯子
Yeah.
好吧
Okay,well,you see in the funny pages.
好 珍重再见吧
What now?
现在怎么办?
I don't know.
我不知道
Van Pelt found some coded files in Bertram's flash drive.
Van Pelt在Bertram的闪存里 发现了代码文件
Should we get started on those?
我们该从那个着手吗?
No,it's a waste of time. We're done.
不 那是浪费时间 我们完工了
There's nothing more to do here.
这儿没什么要做的了
Just go home, get some rest.
回家休息吧
You're not quitting. I don't believe it.
你不是要收手吧 我不相信
No,I'm not quitting.
不 我不是收手
I'm letting go.
我只是放手
It's out of our hands for now.
现在的局面不由我们控制
But I'll be in touch. Okay?
但我们保持联络 好吗?
=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- -=http://ytet.org=-   proudly presents
-------------------------- 本论坛字幕仅翻译交流学习之用 禁止任何商业用途否则后果自负 --------------------------
-=http://bbs.sfile2012.com=- sync:谁能告诉我这是啥狗屁剧情?
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组-歆组=- 翻译: 粒粒尘 紫月 皮皮 Scenery Shirley 校对: 黄沙舞风 时间轴: 谁能告诉我这是啥狗屁剧情?